KASSIDY RALPH

(918) 850-9870 | kassidy.ralph@gmail.com

Analytical, self-driven professional with extensive experience in financial planning and analysis, management consulting, business modeling, and corporate strategy across large public and Fortune 500 companies. Highly dedicated and service-oriented Finance Manager with the ability to expedite finance processes to guarantee data integrity and efficient analyses. A strong communicator with outstanding financial acumen to translate financial information to various business audiences. Demonstrates unmatched capacities to manage multiple projects and balance sophisticated financial statements while maintaining attention to detail. Possesses a proven track record of owning financial models and forecasts to support leadership and drive informed decision making in order to achieve financial targets.

KEY SKILLS

Project Management Skills
Stakeholder Management
Capital Planning Processes

Team Leadership & Management
Financial Planning and Analysis
Continuous Improvements
Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP)
Budget & Financial Forecasts

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lowe's | Remote

Finance Manager, Store Operations Central FP&A

June 2020 - Present

- Serve as a financial subject matter expert to functional leaders; chair the consolidation and presentation of all Store Operations Non-SSC Expense detail for 2H Replan, LRP, and AOP
- Lead in-depth analysis of performance drivers for the Monthly Business Review of Store Support Center Expenses; provide data-driven insights that support decisions and proactively identify financial risks and opportunities
- Drive process improvements such as upgrading existing models used to review financials and analyze variances; designed a dashboard that facilitates real-time SSC data analysis; boosted the efficiency of performing monthly variance analysis
- Formulate business case models to evaluate short- and long-term strategic projects; align support needs and dependencies of stakeholders among multiple functional groups, including Merchandising, Finance Systems, and Operations; define timelines and provide project management for company-wide finance forecasting and planning activities

Chico's FAS | Fort Myers, FL

Sr. Brand Planner, Brand Planning & Strategy

September 2019 - May 2020

- Executed channel-level analyses to align sales and margin budgets; performed sales risk assessments and business model scenarios to determine ROI on products and influence future floor set buys
- Performed data mining with large data sets to identify and analyze trends and sales performance drivers; worked collaboratively with the corresponding owners to devise proactive solutions to address problems
- Measured the impacts of strategic plans on inventory, margin, and customer behavior based on various metrics such as traffic, conversion, AUR, and UPT; create detailed reports for the leadership team based on results
- Spearheaded product testing, including test design and analytics to evaluate consumer response and the product's market performance against specific key performance indicators (KPIs); analyzed data to make recommendations on product changes
- Partnered with the marketing team to coordinate events with the sales plan; drove increased customer engagement, sales, and revenue growth

Zappos Family of Companies | Las Vegas, NV

Manager, FP&A

February 2018 – August 2019

- Led the monthly and annual financial planning process to ensure alignment with the Amazon's annual operating plans; devised operational and financial benchmarks for native and FBA sales to grow the client base and achieve targets
- Collaborated intensively with cross-functional partners that may include CEO, CFO, or COO to review consumer analysis; delivered consultation on effective business planning and expansion strategies to propel consistent growth
- Assessed and recognized improvement areas in the current business procedures; coordinated with Amazon counterparts to develop new approaches and implement an improved allocation methodology; mitigated the issues and reduced allocated expenses by -\$30M annually
- Consolidated inputs from the finance teams to establish a comprehensive P&L for forecasting and budgeting purposes; created financial models and analysis to identify and collectively address areas with discrepancies
- Partnered with the brand marketing team to research and uncover new business opportunities; performed an in-depth financial analysis for new business lines to determine profitability potential; advised key stakeholders on risks and opportunities to help them make sound business decisions
- Worked in close cooperation with a team to develop an internal finance tool that aligned with the business owner's needs
 and metrics; provided full transparency of financial data to organizational groups that enabled the efficient management of
 individual P&Ls

The Hertz Corporation | Estero, FL

Manager, Budget Planning & Forecasting

May 2016 – January 2018

Collaborated with business partners to formulate and maintain financial models for monthly P&L forecasting for U.S.
operations; analyzed and identified key drivers of revenue and expenses; leveraged strong analytical skills in building
quantitative budgeting and forecasting models to effectively calculate P&L projections for each business line

- Analyzed month-end financial reports against the most recent budget submission and forecast to identify variances and its causes; generated detailed reports and presented results to the SVP of Finance
- Worked closely with a team of software engineering consultants to develop and implement the Hyperion-based budgeting tool; streamlined budgeting processes which significantly increased productivity and efficiency; appropriately allocated a division level target to all field locations
- Applied in-depth understandings of GAAP and P&L to execute a more detailed analysis of expenditures; coordinated with the accounting team to restructure accounts to drive better financial results

Sr. Financial Analyst, US RAC Finance

July 2015 - May 2016

- Designed the High Five Weekly Performance presentations and support materials for weekly Executive Council meetings; proactively liaised with business partners to produce scalable performance metrics (KPI) reports to help the CEO recognize and place focus on most significant business areas
- Provided analytical support and performed thorough analysis of financial data and metrics results; identified gaps and built data sets to address critical business questions
- Served as the team's subject matter expert for Hyperion System; devised a financial reporting booklet of 100+ monthly reports; expedited the process of obtaining detailed P&L performance reports against budget and the recent forecast

Financial Analyst, FP&A

August 2014 – July 2015

- Generated and customized ad hoc presentation materials for the Board of Directors' meetings as requested by the CFO;
 provided senior leadership with comprehensive and reliable financial documentation
- Pioneered the monthly preparation of global labor spend, headcount, and productivity reports to determine consistency with the staffing plan and headcount operating budgets
- Interacted closely with HR partners to create tracking for both field and corporate employees; established and enforced a standard reporting package to produce better business decisions

Sr. Pricing Analyst, HERC

January 2014 - August 2014

- Developed pricing models based on market conditions, competition, inventory, and transportation costs; rendered
 predictive/prescriptive analytics and demand planning to support the sales team in making informed decisions on product
 offer structuring
- Maintained and instituted databases to provide visibility and intelligence to various business units; extracted, combined, and strategically organized data for easy access and utilization
- Worked with large sales data sets using MS Access to analyze and synthesize information; employed excellent capacities in written communications to generate reports and recommendations for the sales management team

Dollar Thrifty Automotive Group | Tulsa, OK

Manager, Financial Planning

January 2012 - December 2013

- Oversaw the forecasting of sales and expenses for the Reservations Department; delivered highly accurate profit
 projections to the FP&A team for monthly forecasts and annual budget preparation
- Led strategic planning team with 3 members through monthly forecasting and annual budget development processes; analyzed financial performance against budget and actual forecasts; reported results to the leadership team
- Evaluated financial results and associated reporting; recommended an appropriate course of actions based on findings to achieve improved business outcomes

Sr. Analyst, Budgeting & Planning

January 2011 – January 2012

- Created annual long-range forecasts and profit projections for the Reservations Department; forecasted various metrics such as average call time, calls per hour, and daily reservations based on trends
- Conducted cost-benefit analysis for new project proposals; evaluated new contracts with third-party providers, including fee structure to recognize the financial impact of the proposed change
- Showcased strong attention to detail through careful analysis of financial and business performance metrics; articulately
 presented findings to guide senior leadership on budget needs and decisions

EDUCATION

Oklahoma State University | Stillwater, OK

January 2014 - May 2015

Computer Science related courses completed in Information Systems; Information Technology Forensics; Operating in Entrepreneurial Firms; Management of Sustainable Enterprises; Entrepreneurial Marketing

Oklahoma State University | Stillwater, OK

Master of Business Administration, Major in Business Administration Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Major in Management Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Major in Finance August 2009 – December 2013 August 2008 – May 2009 August 2004 – May 2008

CERTIFICATION

Oklahoma State University | Stillwater, OK SAS and OSU Business Analytics Certification

August 2009 - May 2013

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Microsoft Excel/Advanced Excel (Macros, Power Pivot), Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Access, Cognos, ThinkCell, Prophix, SAP, Hyperion, Essbase, Oracle, JD Edwards, SQL, Tableau, Python, ERP